No mercy. No shame. No sequel.
Scary Movie is a comedy film directed by Keenen Ivory Wayans.
A familiar-looking group of teenagers find themselves being stalked
by a more-than-vaguely recognizable masked killer!
As the victims begin to pile up and the laughs pile on, none of your favorite scary
movies escape the razor-sharp satire of this outrageously funny parody!
Cindy Campbell, played by Anna Faris.
Bobby Prinze, played by Jon Abrahams.
Greg Phillippe, played by Lochlyn Munro.
Shorty Meeks, played by Marlon Wayans.
Ray Wilkins, played by Shawn Wayans.
Brenda Meeks, played by Regina Hall.
Scary Movie is a 2000 American slasher parody film directed by Keenen Ivory Wayans and written by Marlon and Shawn
Wayans (who both also star), alongside Buddy Johnson, Phil Beauman, Jason Friedberg and Aaron Seltzer.
Starring Jon Abrahams, Carmen Electra, Shannon Elizabeth, Anna Faris, Kurt Fuller, Regina Hall, Lochlyn Munro, Cheri Oteri, and Dave
Sheridan, it follows a group of teenagers who accidentally hit a man with their car, dump his body in a lake, and swear to secrecy.
A year later, someone wearing a Ghostface mask and
robe begins hunting them one by one.
Miramax Films, through their then-subsidiary label Dimension Films,
released Scary Movie in the United States on July 7, 2000.
The film grossed $278 million worldwide on a $19 million
budget and is the highest-grossing in the series.
It was the ninth-highest-grossing film of the year
domestically in the United States.
The film is the first installment in the Scary Movie film series.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and later spawned
five sequels, starting with  Scary Movie 2 in 2001.
The film explores themes of high school, psychopath, garage, satire, parody.
The tone is lighthearted.